Shevon Denny

New York, New York | 347-383-3646 | shevoncdenny@gmail.com Github | Blog | LinkedIn | Personal Website

SUMMARY

Full stack software engineer on a journey of continuous improvement and growth. My passion for learning and problem solving has driven me to challenge myself to learn how to code. My experiences in design, retail and hospitality enables me to be hands-on, open-minded, collaborate well with my peers and have a keen eye for detail.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React, JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, Python, Node.js, SQL, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS

PROJECTS

Hairsuit - Github front-end | Github back-end | Demo video

Salon finder app where users can search for a salon based on specialty or salon name, post/delete a review/appointment.

- Stored encrypted user information client-side using JSON Web Tokens and localStorage.
- Executed an image upload by implementing active storage to display the user salon review.
- Utilized Postgresql as a backend storage database to return data to the front-end.
- Configured and performed CRUD operations using Ruby on Rails and React.

Let's Hang - Github | Demo video

Using Foursquare API a user can search venues and plan meet-ups. Favorite a "hang" spot to return to in the future.

- Implemented API endpoints to extract data in order to perform functionalities and display content client-side.
- Created RESTful routes utilizing Ruby on Rails to return data.
- Styled and designed app using styled components to display UI.

Artsy - Github front-end | Github back-end | Demo video

Art gallery finder, where a user can buy artwork or view upcoming shows. Add/remove artwork to the user's collection.

- Utilized Active Record and Sinatra to carry out back end functionalities.
- Displayed content and performed functionalities using React.
- Constructed app using multiple React libraries and frameworks to make the app aesthetically pleasing.

EXPERIENCE

Vonshe Brooklyn, NY Freelance Fashion Designer Jan 2017 - Present

- Design and construct paper patterns for garments then execute garment construction from start to finish.
- Market garments/products to reach desired target audience.
- Record and manage financial affairs of the business.

O Café New York, NY

Barista/Server Sept 2017 - January 2021

- Created latte art for every customer to showcase my creativity and brighten customers day.
- Built lasting relationships with customers to ensure their return.

Brooklyn, NY **Applebees**

Server/Bartender/Neighborhood expert

Interacted verbally with all bar patrons, creating a friendly and upbeat atmosphere, through outstanding customer service.

June 2015 - Dec 2016

Increased customer turnover by creating a system in which bartenders would be able to easily serve bar patrons and restaurant guests in a quick and efficient manner.

H&M New York, NY Nov 2011 - Aug 2015 Sales Advisor

Optimized the store's sales by providing customers with help and insight for a pleasant shopping experience.

- Recognized and executed selling opportunities to meet daily sales goals.
- Styled garments and accessories to create an outfit to appeal to customers.
- Maintained a clean department in a fast paced environment to ensure garments were easily accessible for shoppers.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School New York, NY Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program May 2021 - Aug 2021

Borough of Manhattan Community College

New York, NY Completed courses in Business Management, Marketing Aug 2013 - Jan 2015